Alex Borsody

St Petersburg, Florida, United States



linkedin.com/in/alexborsody



asborsody@gmail.com



https://alexborsody.github.io/



914 715 8862

Summary

over 15 years experience as a Full-stack developer with a unique combination of backend engineering skills, frontend layout/design, and product owner vision. Strictly heads down programming can stifle creativity which makes it harder to look at the actual product and it's usefulness. I translate business requirements and get to work, getting the job done.

I always gravitate to the latest technologies, which these days would be the most popular JS frameworks React/Angular, but also have developed native apps in iOS and Swift. My focus is on working with CMS's as a RESTful API for mobile apps I have been pushing these technologies forward since these headless development was in its infancy. I focus on whatever the best tool is to get the job done.

Experience



Horizon Fuel Limited

Jan 2017 - Present (3 years 4 months +)

Forward thinking membership based rapid growth discount card startup. In charge of building out IT infrastructure. Android/iOS apps and Drupal based website, extensive third party API integration.

Software Engineer Team Lead

Free Energy Media

Mar 2010 - Present (10 years 2 months +)

I work with Fortune 500 and boutique companies alike. Focusing on companies that make a positive impact on society. I build software and lead teams of software developers to get the job done.

Open source projects and research include emerging progressive web app technologies (PWA). I maintain the D8 branch of the PWA module on Drupal.org https://www.drupal.org/project/pwa

Successful projects can be shown and run through in more detail including financial institutions Markel (REST API/D8), Moodys, Goldman Sachs (Javascript), The US military (Drupal/JS), Baseball Hall of Fame (Android Studio), Wanderlust Music Festival (Wordpress), NBC Biggest Loser (Drupal), Google/Apigee (Drupal), Qualcomm (Android Studio), Internet Society the financial arm of Internet Engineering Task Force IETF (Wordpress/Drupal), Lands' End (Javascript). Countless other projects for non-marquee clients as well.

See my Linkedin for recommendation section and more details on projects.

As I am under NDA for many clients details of projects are limited in some cases.



Web Developer II

Thomasnet

Mar 2008 - Mar 2010 (2 years 1 month)

Education

Eckerd College

Bachelor's degree 2002 - 2006

📘 University of South Florida

Information Systems 2007 - 2008

Skills

JavaScript • Drupal • Project Management • Mobile Applications • Django • React.js • PHP • Open Source Software • System Administration • WordPress